<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<protocol name="xdg_decoration_unstable_v1">
  <copyright>
    Copyright © 2018 Simon Ser

    Permission is hereby granted, free of charge, to any person obtaining a
    copy of this software and associated documentation files (the "Software"),
    to deal in the Software without restriction, including without limitation
    the rights to use, copy, modify, merge, publish, distribute, sublicense,
    and/or sell copies of the Software, and to permit persons to whom the
    Software is furnished to do so, subject to the following conditions:

    The above copyright notice and this permission notice (including the next
    paragraph) shall be included in all copies or substantial portions of the
    Software.

    THE SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED "AS IS", WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR
    IMPLIED, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY,
    FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE AND NONINFRINGEMENT.  IN NO EVENT SHALL
    THE AUTHORS OR COPYRIGHT HOLDERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY CLAIM, DAMAGES OR OTHER
    LIABILITY, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, TORT OR OTHERWISE, ARISING
    FROM, OUT OF OR IN CONNECTION WITH THE SOFTWARE OR THE USE OR OTHER
    DEALINGS IN THE SOFTWARE.
  </copyright>

  <interface name="zxdg_decoration_manager_v1" version="1">
    <description summary="window decoration manager">
      This interface allows a compositor to announce support for server-side
      decorations.

      A window decoration is a set of window controls as deemed appropriate by
      the party managing them, such as user interface components used to move,
      resize and change a window's state.

      A client can use this protocol to request being decorated by a supporting
      compositor.

      If compositor and client do not negotiate the use of a server-side
      decoration using this protocol, clients continue to self-decorate as they
      see fit.

      Warning! The protocol described in this file is experimental and
      backward incompatible changes may be made. Backward compatible changes
      may be added together with the corresponding interface version bump.
      Backward incompatible changes are done by bumping the version number in
      the protocol and interface names and resetting the interface version.
      Once the protocol is to be declared stable, the 'z' prefix and the
      version number in the protocol and interface names are removed and the
      interface version number is reset.
    </description>

    <request name="destroy" type="destructor">
      <description summary="destroy the decoration manager object">
        Destroy the decoration manager. This doesn't destroy objects created
        with the manager.
      </description>
    </request>

    <request name="get_toplevel_decoration">
      <description summary="create a new toplevel decoration object">
        Create a new decoration object associated with the given toplevel.

        Creating an xdg_toplevel_decoration from an xdg_toplevel which has a
        buffer attached or committed is a client error, and any attempts by a
        client to attach or manipulate a buffer prior to the first
        xdg_toplevel_decoration.configure event must also be treated as
        errors.
      </description>
      <arg name="id" type="new_id" interface="zxdg_toplevel_decoration_v1"/>
      <arg name="toplevel" type="object" interface="xdg_toplevel"/>
    </request>
  </interface>

  <interface name="zxdg_toplevel_decoration_v1" version="1">
    <description summary="decoration object for a toplevel surface">
      The decoration object allows the client to negotiate the rendering of
      the window decorations.

      The client is responsible for creating an xdg_toplevel_decoration object
      and telling the compositor what mode it wants to use.

      The compositor will deliver to the client the current mode via a
      configure event.

      The client must use the actual mode received in the configure event.

      A switch to a different mode works as follows:
      - The client requests a new mode via set_mode.
      - The compositor receives the request.
      - The compositor sends a configure event with the new mode.
      - The client receives the configure event.
      The client can use the new mode as soon as it receives the configure
      event.

      The client can also request a preferred mode at any time. The compositor
      is free to ignore this request.

      The client issues a set_mode request with the desired mode.
      The compositor replies with a configure event with the new mode.

      The compositor is free to choose its own mode if the client has not
      requested one.

      The compositor is free to deny the request.

      The compositor must reply to a set_mode request with a configure event.
      The client must track the new mode.

      The client may also receive a configure event at any time.

      The client can use the mode interface to request a mode.
    </description>

    <enum name="error">
      <entry name="unconfigured_buffer" value="0"
             summary="xdg_toplevel has a buffer attached before configure"/>
      <entry name="already_constructed" value="1"
             summary="xdg_toplevel already has a decoration object"/>
      <entry name="orphaned" value="2"
             summary="xdg_toplevel destroyed before the decoration object"/>
    </enum>

    <enum name="mode">
      <description summary="window decoration modes">
        These values describe window decoration modes.
      </description>
      <entry name="client_side" value="1"
             summary="no server-side window decoration"/>
      <entry name="server_side" value="2"
             summary="server-side window decoration"/>
    </enum>

    <request name="destroy" type="destructor">
      <description summary="destroy the decoration object">
        Switch back to a mode without any server-side decorations at the next
        commit.
      </description>
    </request>

    <request name="set_mode">
      <description summary="set the decoration mode">
        Set the preferred decoration mode.

        The compositor will check whether the requested mode is available.
        If it is, the compositor will send a configure event with the
        requested mode.
        If it is not, the compositor will send a configure event with a
        fallback mode.

        The client must follow the mode received in the configure event.
      </description>
      <arg name="mode" type="uint" enum="mode" summary="the decoration mode"/>
    </request>

    <request name="unset_mode">
      <description summary="unset the decoration mode">
        Unset the preferred decoration mode. The compositor will choose a
        mode.
      </description>
    </request>

    <event name="configure">
      <description summary="suggest a surface change">
        The configure event asks the client to change its decoration mode.
        The configured state should not be applied immediately. See
        xdg_surface.configure for details.

        A configure event can be sent at any time. The specified mode must be
        obeyed by the client.
      </description>
      <arg name="mode" type="uint" enum="mode" summary="the decoration mode"/>
    </event>
  </interface>
</protocol>
